<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nordic Skiing on Daniel Kerwin</title>
    <link>http://danielwkerwin.com/tags/nordic-skiing/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nordic Skiing on Daniel Kerwin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://danielwkerwin.com/tags/nordic-skiing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Birkebeiner is baptism by fire for rookie Nordic skiers</title>
      <link>http://danielwkerwin.com/2017/02/birkebeiner-is-baptism-by-fire-for-rookie-nordic-skiers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danielwkerwin.com/2017/02/birkebeiner-is-baptism-by-fire-for-rookie-nordic-skiers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Here is an article of mine that was published in The Mac Weekly on February 26, 2010 about the Macalester Nordic ski team&amp;rsquo;s participation in the Birkebeiner race.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ST. PAUL - If the brief walk between buildings on campus is sometimes too much for you during the harsh winter months, then you can appreciate how grueling a sport Nordic skiing is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow, members of Macalester’s Nordic ski team will be taking on one of the sport’s toughest challenges, enduring hours of exposure to the elements as they compete in the American Birkebeiner in northern Wisconsin. It’s not just an average race, but one that coach Ari Ofsevit ’06 describes as “by far the largest and most prestigious race in the [Western] hemisphere.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides being perhaps the most well known race in America, it’s also one of the most challenging. The event is comprised of three main races, the longest measuring a grueling 54 km. To put this in perspective, a full length marathon is just over 42 km.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The race is tough for even the most experienced skiers, and this year a number of Macalester students are competing in the event for the first time. Some of them don’t have any Nordic ski racing experience at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latter is particularly true for Terrence Steinberg ’11. Despite having experience in endurance sports such as triathlon, Steinberg is brand new to Nordic skiing. The Birkebeiner will be his first ever race, and he’ll be participating in the longest of the three races, the 54 km classic race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In looking toward the race, Steinberg said “I’m optimistic. Even though I don’t have the best technique or most experience, it’ll be an adrenaline rush and I’ll just have fun.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of his choice to take up Nordic skiing, he said “I just wanted to learn a new sport and use it for cross training, work on my endurance and stuff and be outdoors.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emil Mellgren ’10 is coming into the Birkebeiner from a similar place to Steinberg. A fellow triathlete, Mellgren joined the team with a background in Nordic skiing but without any racing experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steinberg and Mellgren are just two of the many new members on the team this year. The team was cut as a varsity sport back in 2003, and in recent years has struggled to gain many members.  This year a large crop of experienced first years as well as new upperclassmen like Steinberg and Mellgren has made the team huge, perhaps saving the program from further woes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the experienced new first years is Tess Carley ’13. Carley raced heavily in high school, but mostly shorter races; her previous longest race was 33 km. Tomorrow she’ll be competing in the 50 km freestyle race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The 33K was one of the longest days of my life, so I’m a little bit nervous to add on 17 more,” Carley said. “Nordic skiing is just really tiring. I’m hoping to reach a point where I don’t feel my arms anymore, or my legs, that’ll make it easier.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fellow first year Tommy Symms ’13 has already started looking at what waits beyond the race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s going to be sweet to be able to brag about doing the biggest race in the Western Hemisphere,” Symms said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While finishing the race in the first place hold enough bragging rights in of itself, the team is looking to make an even bigger impact at the race. The team has entered three teams in the competition, a combination of two over the two longer races and one in the shorter 23 km Kortelopet race. The team will be led by Collin Cousins ’10, who is skiing in the elite wave of the race and is looking to finish in the top 50 in a total field of over 8000 competitors. Ofsevit, who despite being the coach will also be skiing in the elite wave as a member of the team, likes Macalester’s chances of placing high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I think we have a decent chance to win some hardware,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Sarah Van Etten ’10, racing the Birkie is addictive. “Once you get bitten by the bug you can’t stop doing it,” she said. Van Etten grew up in Spooner, a town about an hour away from the course, and for her each year the Birkie is a huge family event. Come tomorrow morning the first time Birkebeiner skiers on the team will be able to understand why the Birkebeiner is so close to the hearts of so many Nordic skiers the world over.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nordic team skis with the best at the Birkebeiner race</title>
      <link>http://danielwkerwin.com/2017/02/nordic-team-skis-with-the-best-at-the-birkebeiner-race/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danielwkerwin.com/2017/02/nordic-team-skis-with-the-best-at-the-birkebeiner-race/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Here is an article of mine that was published in The Mac Weekly on March 5, 2010 about the Macalester Nordic ski team&amp;rsquo;s results in the Birkebeiner race.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ST. PAUL - The leader of the Tour de France wears a yellow jersey, but the leader of Macalester&amp;rsquo;s Nordic ski team wears&amp;hellip; pink ski boots? At least that was the case when the team competed in the American Birkebeiner last Saturday, with Collin Cousins &amp;lsquo;10 sporting pink boots as he skied to a 32nd place finish in the race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cousins finished with an outstanding time of 2:04:57.4 in the 50 kilometer race, by far the race of his life, but he wasn&amp;rsquo;t the only Macalester skier passing scores of other racers in the field of over 8,000 competitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Everyone had good skis and good times, and Collin did extremely well, he was shooting for the top 50 but got 32nd in a pretty tough field,&amp;rdquo; coach Ari Ofsevit &amp;lsquo;06 said. &amp;ldquo;Everyone should be really happy with what they got out of the race.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cousins has skied the Birkebeiner well in the past and qualified to race in the elite wave of the field, but his result on Saturday has taken him to a whole new level in the sport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Given that I started training in January, I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to finish with the top guys, but I felt strong, pushed to my max, and had fun,&amp;rdquo; Cousins said. &amp;ldquo;The race result means that I need to make a decision whether or not to pursue racing on a professional level or continue to enjoy it casually.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ofsevit said that if Cousins chooses to focus hard on ski training after graduating in May he has the potential to have a bright future in the sport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;He&amp;rsquo;s the kind of guy that with training he could turn out some really top level results; he&amp;rsquo;s pretty darn close already,&amp;rdquo; Ofsevit said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although Cousins came into the race as a seasoned skier, most of the team was competing in the Birkebeiner for the first time. Many of these skiers were optimistic when interviewed before the race in last week&amp;rsquo;s Mac Weekly. This optimism turned out to be completely justified. Macalester placed highly compared to other collegiate teams in the event, finishing fourth in the full length Birkebeiner and first in the shorter Kortelopet race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Terence Steinberg &amp;lsquo;11 was one of the first time racers who had a good experience in not only his first ever Birkebeiner, but his first ever ski race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It was a lot easier than I thought it would be,&amp;rdquo; Steinberg said. &amp;ldquo;I was worried I&amp;rsquo;d have to go in and be humbled by the whole thing, but it was actually a huge confidence booster, which was really sweet.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emil Mellgren &amp;lsquo;10 was also racing for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Something you ask yourself is &amp;lsquo;Why am I doing this?&amp;rsquo; - your body wants you to stop, but it&amp;rsquo;s a really good feeling when you keep going,&amp;rdquo; Mellgren said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Birkebeiner has become an obsession for skiers worldwide. Mellgren experienced this when he unexpectedly ran into a family friend from Sweden while competing. The race has become so popular that fans line vast stretches of the course of the race, which ends on the streets of downtown Hayward, Wis. Tess Carley &amp;lsquo;13 appreciated the support the spectators provided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Saturday was a beautiful day and it was crazy to be amongst so many Nordic skiers,&amp;rdquo; Carley said. &amp;ldquo;All of the crazy fans cheering along the way made it easier to finish, and there was a lot of adrenaline after waking up at 5:30 to ski with 8,400 other people.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team made vast progress with all the new skiers this season, the culmination of which was seen at the Birkebeiner, boding well for the program&amp;rsquo;s future. However, the team will suffer a blow with a large proportion of the team graduating this May.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I think we fared really well as a team,&amp;rdquo; Steinberg said. &amp;ldquo;Unfortunately most of the team is seniors this year so we won&amp;rsquo;t be able to build on it as much as we could have.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However the team is always open to have new people come out and try the sport. Ofsevit stresses that the program isn&amp;rsquo;t concerned foremost with racing results, but that &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s really about going out, having a good time and improving year after year and month after month.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ofsevit will be holding a clinic this Sunday for anyone who is interested in learning how to ski, and absolute beginners are more than welcome. Details can be found alongside this article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For anyone who is interested in trying Nordic skiing, Steinberg and Mellgren are two good examples that Nordic skiing is a good way not only to get out and enjoy the winter months, but it potentially opens new doors too. Both intend to compete in a biathlon event this Sunday, the first time either will have attempted the sport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There&amp;rsquo;s just something about skiing around in the woods with a gun on your back that speaks to the Northern Swede in me,&amp;rdquo; Mellgren said. &amp;ldquo;Maybe that&amp;rsquo;ll be next year&amp;rsquo;s project.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>