<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sports on Daniel Kerwin</title>
    <link>http://danielwkerwin.com/tags/sports/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sports on Daniel Kerwin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://danielwkerwin.com/tags/sports/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Birkebeiner is baptism by fire for rookie Nordic skiers</title>
      <link>http://danielwkerwin.com/2017/02/birkebeiner-is-baptism-by-fire-for-rookie-nordic-skiers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danielwkerwin.com/2017/02/birkebeiner-is-baptism-by-fire-for-rookie-nordic-skiers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Here is an article of mine that was published in The Mac Weekly on February 26, 2010 about the Macalester Nordic ski team&amp;rsquo;s participation in the Birkebeiner race.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ST. PAUL - If the brief walk between buildings on campus is sometimes too much for you during the harsh winter months, then you can appreciate how grueling a sport Nordic skiing is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow, members of Macalester’s Nordic ski team will be taking on one of the sport’s toughest challenges, enduring hours of exposure to the elements as they compete in the American Birkebeiner in northern Wisconsin. It’s not just an average race, but one that coach Ari Ofsevit ’06 describes as “by far the largest and most prestigious race in the [Western] hemisphere.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides being perhaps the most well known race in America, it’s also one of the most challenging. The event is comprised of three main races, the longest measuring a grueling 54 km. To put this in perspective, a full length marathon is just over 42 km.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The race is tough for even the most experienced skiers, and this year a number of Macalester students are competing in the event for the first time. Some of them don’t have any Nordic ski racing experience at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latter is particularly true for Terrence Steinberg ’11. Despite having experience in endurance sports such as triathlon, Steinberg is brand new to Nordic skiing. The Birkebeiner will be his first ever race, and he’ll be participating in the longest of the three races, the 54 km classic race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In looking toward the race, Steinberg said “I’m optimistic. Even though I don’t have the best technique or most experience, it’ll be an adrenaline rush and I’ll just have fun.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of his choice to take up Nordic skiing, he said “I just wanted to learn a new sport and use it for cross training, work on my endurance and stuff and be outdoors.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emil Mellgren ’10 is coming into the Birkebeiner from a similar place to Steinberg. A fellow triathlete, Mellgren joined the team with a background in Nordic skiing but without any racing experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steinberg and Mellgren are just two of the many new members on the team this year. The team was cut as a varsity sport back in 2003, and in recent years has struggled to gain many members.  This year a large crop of experienced first years as well as new upperclassmen like Steinberg and Mellgren has made the team huge, perhaps saving the program from further woes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the experienced new first years is Tess Carley ’13. Carley raced heavily in high school, but mostly shorter races; her previous longest race was 33 km. Tomorrow she’ll be competing in the 50 km freestyle race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The 33K was one of the longest days of my life, so I’m a little bit nervous to add on 17 more,” Carley said. “Nordic skiing is just really tiring. I’m hoping to reach a point where I don’t feel my arms anymore, or my legs, that’ll make it easier.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fellow first year Tommy Symms ’13 has already started looking at what waits beyond the race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s going to be sweet to be able to brag about doing the biggest race in the Western Hemisphere,” Symms said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While finishing the race in the first place hold enough bragging rights in of itself, the team is looking to make an even bigger impact at the race. The team has entered three teams in the competition, a combination of two over the two longer races and one in the shorter 23 km Kortelopet race. The team will be led by Collin Cousins ’10, who is skiing in the elite wave of the race and is looking to finish in the top 50 in a total field of over 8000 competitors. Ofsevit, who despite being the coach will also be skiing in the elite wave as a member of the team, likes Macalester’s chances of placing high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I think we have a decent chance to win some hardware,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Sarah Van Etten ’10, racing the Birkie is addictive. “Once you get bitten by the bug you can’t stop doing it,” she said. Van Etten grew up in Spooner, a town about an hour away from the course, and for her each year the Birkie is a huge family event. Come tomorrow morning the first time Birkebeiner skiers on the team will be able to understand why the Birkebeiner is so close to the hearts of so many Nordic skiers the world over.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Huskies headed to state</title>
      <link>http://danielwkerwin.com/2017/02/huskies-headed-to-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danielwkerwin.com/2017/02/huskies-headed-to-state/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Here is an article of mine that was published in the Worthington Daily Globe on March 12, 2011 about the Jackson County Central girls&amp;rsquo; basketball team&amp;rsquo;s qualification for the state tournament.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


 
  
  
  
  
    
      
    
  
    
      
    
  
    
  
    
      
    
  

 
  
  
  
  
    
  
    
      
    
  
    
      
    
  

&lt;div class=&#34;figure center fig-100&#34; &gt;
  
    &lt;a class=&#34;fancybox&#34; href=&#34;http://res.cloudinary.com/danielwkerwin/image/upload/v1487032334/JCC_girls_basketball_with_plaque_March_12_2011_ylmxud.jpg&#34; title=&#34;The Jackson County Central girls&amp;#39; basketball team celebrates its Section Championship victory against Yellow Medicine East.&#34; data-fancybox-group=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  
    &lt;img class=&#34;fig-img&#34; src=&#34;http://res.cloudinary.com/danielwkerwin/image/upload/v1487032334/JCC_girls_basketball_with_plaque_March_12_2011_ylmxud.jpg&#34;  alt=&#34;The Jackson County Central girls&amp;#39; basketball team celebrates its Section Championship victory against Yellow Medicine East.&#34;&gt;
  
    &lt;/a&gt;
  
   
    &lt;span class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;The Jackson County Central girls&amp;#39; basketball team celebrates its Section Championship victory against Yellow Medicine East.&lt;/span&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div style=&#34;clear:both;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;MARSHALL &amp;ndash; Thanks to a determined all-around team effort and a well-executed 13-0 first-half run, the ever-hustling Jackson County Central Huskies are state bound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, the Huskies improved to 26-2 for the season and earned their way to the 2011 state high school girls&amp;rsquo; basketball tournament by capturing the Section 3AA championship Friday night with a 57-41 victory over Yellow Medicine East at the R / A Facility on the campus of Southwest Minnesota State University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This is awesome, just awesome,&amp;rdquo; declared an elated JCC senior forward Brittney Kruse following the post-game awards ceremony. &amp;ldquo;This is what I&amp;rsquo;ve worked for my whole high school career.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kruse, who is called &amp;ldquo;Old Faithful&amp;rdquo; by JCC head coach Tom Schuller, for her remarkable reliability and consistency, scored eight of her 10 points in the first half Friday night, including the team&amp;rsquo;s first four, as the Huskies struggled to score in the opening minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Our shooting was a little off at first, but we knew that we had to hustle, play hard on defense and rebound,&amp;rdquo; summed up Kruse about the game&amp;rsquo;s start. &amp;ldquo;Then, once our shots started falling, we put a nice run of points together.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kruse was one of four JCC players who scored in double figures in the contest, as the well-balanced Huskies never trailed in the game after 5-10 junior forward Kaylee Benson (team-high 15 points, four rebounds, two steals) connected on the first of her 3-pointers, snapping an early 4-4 deadlock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After stringing together 13 unanswered points &amp;ndash; which changed a 7-6 lead to a 20-6 advantage during a span of three minutes and 34 seconds, from the 10:02 mark to when 6:28 showed on the first-half clock &amp;ndash; JCC took a 33-19 advantage into intermission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the second half, the Huskies had several 13-point leads and held wider spreads of 41-25, 43-27 and 47-29 before the Sting scored seven straight points to trim JCC&amp;rsquo;s lead to 47-36 with 6:56 left in the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Southwest Conference champions, however, responded with a 6-0 run and with 5:39 to play had increased their lead back to 17 points, 53-36.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Controlling the ball well, the Huskies maintained an advantage of 15 to 18 points the rest of the contest, earning the school&amp;rsquo;s first trip back to the Class AA state tournament since 2004.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;That feels so good,&amp;rdquo; exclaimed senior Courtney Kruse, Brittney&amp;rsquo;s twin sister. &amp;ldquo;Winning this game and going to the state tournament means a lot. It&amp;rsquo;s so awesome and it&amp;rsquo;s what we&amp;rsquo;ve all been working for all year long.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Courtney Kruse scored six of her 10 points after intermission, hitting several clutch shots from the right wing, helping JCC maintain its lead through a nearly evenly-played second half.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fourth JCC player to notch double figures was 5-5 senior guard Leslie Handzus, who netted 12 points and dished off a game-high nine assists, to go along with five rebounds and a pair of steals. She also deflected seven passes, helping JCC&amp;rsquo;s diversified pressing tactics disrupt YME&amp;rsquo;s offensive flow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;She is one of the best guards that we have played against,&amp;rdquo; praised YME head coach Scott Jans about Handzus. &amp;ldquo;She is so quick and does it all for JCC.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Steffen&amp;rsquo;s shot from corner sparks JCC run, Handzus has three assists in 3:34&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was lots of action in the game&amp;rsquo;s first seven minutes, but very little scoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JCC came up with the ball often &amp;ndash; both via steal and by rebound &amp;ndash; but the Huskies missed most of their shots, several of which were well off the mark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benson&amp;rsquo;s 3-pointer had given JCC a 7-4 edge at around the 12-minute mark (after two earlier baskets by Brittney Kruse), but a nice drive by YME&amp;rsquo;s Angie Scheffler (10:46) yielded the only two points of the next two minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But with 10:02 on the clock, junior forward Tracey Steffen took a pass from Benson and swished a 16-footer along the left baseline, giving the Huskies a 9-6 edge and triggering what turned out to be a 13-0 run for JCC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;That was a huge shot,&amp;rdquo; beamed Schuller about Steffen&amp;rsquo;s 2-pointer. &amp;ldquo;We count on all of our kids to step up and shoot the ball when the chance is there and Tracey sure made a nice one when we really needed it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brittney Kruse followed with her second offensive-rebound basket of the game and the lead was 11-6.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then after a series of deflected passes, Handzus fired a pass to sophomore forward Marita Rasche for a layup, which gave JCC a 13-6 advantage with 7:55 on the clock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twenty-eight seconds later, Handzus sliced through the retreating YME defense on a transition break down the left sideline and finished with a &amp;ldquo;duck under&amp;rdquo; layup, increasing the lead to eight points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following a timeout by Jans, Handzus handed the ball off to Benson who delivered another 3-pointer and, at the 7:04 mark, the Huskies were up by 10, 18-8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kaylee had a spectacular game,&amp;rdquo; declared Schuller. &amp;ldquo;She has to work so hard on defense, often guarding the other team&amp;rsquo;s leading scorer, and then she&amp;rsquo;s still able to knock down big shots like those.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thirty-two seconds after that, Handzus distributed her third assist of the surge, passing to an open Brittney Kruse in the right corner, who drilled the shot, capping the 13-0 run and giving her team a 20-6 advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YME&amp;rsquo;s Gretchen Rigge scored soon after, snapping the Sting&amp;rsquo;s nearly five-minute drought, but Handzus responded with a 3-pointer from the left corner and with 5:18 to go in the half, JCC was in command, 23-8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The remaining five minutes up to intermission were closely-contested, as the Sting regrouped and put together a 7-2 run, trimming the gap to 25-15.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A flash to the high post by Courtney Kruse (assist Brittney) yielded JCC&amp;rsquo;s only two points during that YME burst.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, the Huskies stayed in control as junior forward Whitney Burmeister and Benson both sank a pair of free throws, Benson scored on a nifty jumper in the lane, and a steal by Courtney Kruse resulted in a Handzus assist to Courtney for a right wing 2-pointer as the half came to a close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benson netted 10 of JCC&amp;rsquo;s first-half points, as a total of seven Huskies scored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;All five starters score as JCC maintains lead&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Handzus (seven) and Courtney Kruse combined for 13 of JCC&amp;rsquo;s second-half points, while Benson (five), Burmeister (four) and Brittney Kruse (two) contributed 11 more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benson&amp;rsquo;s third trey of the game &amp;ndash; from the right corner with 16:25 to play &amp;ndash; increased JCC&amp;rsquo;s lead to 36-21.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sting cut the gap to 11, 36-25, but two free throws by Burmeister made the score 38-25 with 14 minutes left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neither squad scored for several possessions, but a 3-pointer by the ever-versatile Handzus from the deep left corner, lifted JCC to a 41-25 advantage with 12:34 on the clock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Scheffler (eight points) scored on another strong drive for the Sting, the Huskies countered with a basket off a loose ball scramble, which was picked up Rasche (five deflections, three steals) and passed to Courtney Kruse, who passed to her twin sister for a 43-27 JCC lead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another assist from Handzus &amp;ndash; this one to Courtney Kruse &amp;ndash; put the Huskies up by 16 (45-29) with 10:17 to play, and then another steal by Rasche (and her assist) gave Benson 15 points and JCC a 47-29 advantage with 9:05 on the clock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sting, which entered the game having won nine of its last 10 games, rallied briefly with a 7-0 run, but the Huskies stayed ahead as Burmeister attacked &amp;ndash; through YME&amp;rsquo;s press &amp;ndash; for a driving field goal from the high post and the score was 49-36.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick basket by Courtney Kruse and two free throws by Handzus put the Huskies up by 17, 53-36, with just under six minutes remaining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Courtney Kruse twice made one-of-two free throws, Handzus dazzled the crowd with another spectacular left-side drive, increasing the lead to 57-39 with 3:53 on the clock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JCC then effectively controlled the game with its four-corner offense and strong defensive rebounding, winning its 12th consecutive game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We are just really pleased about winning the section championship,&amp;rdquo; summed up Schuller. &amp;ldquo;Whitney Burmeister has been our leading scorer all season, but in this game, it was our outstanding balance that came through &amp;ndash; as four players scored double figures and Whitney wasn&amp;rsquo;t one of them. That&amp;rsquo;s just the type of team we are, all the girls can score and contribute to the total team goal &amp;ndash; which is winning the game.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Burmeister (six points, three steals, two assists, one block) finished with a team-high seven rebounds for the Huskies, while Brittney Kruse had six rebounds, including four on the offensive end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Kruse twins (Brittney, four) combined to deflect seven passes, while Steffen also got her hands on a YME pass, as the Huskies deflected a total of 20 passes in the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;JCC&amp;rsquo;s overall athleticism and their ability to play at a high speed was difficult to overcome,&amp;rdquo; summed up Jans, who will return four starters next season from a team which finished 20-7 and claimed the north sub-section championship with a trio of tournament wins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yellow Medicine East, I think, is a good team,&amp;rdquo; pointed out Schuller. &amp;ldquo;This was not an easy game because they have a nice all-around team, which plays very good defense.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Huskies will play Minnehaha Academy, champions of Section 4AA, at 8 p.m. Wednesday at Target Center in Minneapolis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am so happy for these girls, many of whom have been outstanding multiple-sport performers for us at JCC,&amp;rdquo; concluded Schuller. &amp;ldquo;To get this chance to play in the state tournament is just tremendous for them.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;YME 19 22 &amp;ndash; 41&lt;/br&gt;
JCC 33 24 &amp;ndash; 57&lt;/br&gt;
YME (3FG-2FG-FT-TP) Rigge 0-2-0-4, Larson 1-3-1-10, Jans 0-3-0-6, Hinz 0-1-4-6, Baker 0-3-1-7, Scheffler 0-4-0-8. Totals 1-16-6-41.&lt;/br&gt;
JCC (3FG-2FG-FT-TP) Handzus 2-2-2-12, B. Kruse 0-5-10, Rasche 0-1-0-2, C. Kruse 0-4-2-10, Benson 3-2-2-15, Steffen 0-1-0-2, Burmeister 0-1-4-6. Totals 5-16-10-57.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Huskies on the prowl: Jackson County Central groomed for state tourney run</title>
      <link>http://danielwkerwin.com/2017/02/huskies-on-the-prowl-jackson-county-central-groomed-for-state-tourney-run/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danielwkerwin.com/2017/02/huskies-on-the-prowl-jackson-county-central-groomed-for-state-tourney-run/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Here is an article of mine that was published in the Worthington Daily Globe on February 1, 2011 about the Jackson County Central girls&amp;rsquo; basketball team&amp;rsquo;s pursuit of qualifying for the state tournament.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JACKSON — The Jackson County Central girls’ basketball team doesn’t mind that its undefeated season came to an end with a loss to Marshall on Jan. 25.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The pressure’s off your back,” Huskie junior Whitney Burmeister said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hair is also off the players’ legs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up until the loss, the players and head coach Tom Schuller had made a pact. They wouldn’t shave their legs until they lost, and he wouldn’t cut his hair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea came from Burmeister, who went through the ritual herself last season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Last year I did it, and I tried getting a few others, but they didn’t want to give in then,” Burmeister said. “This year I brought it up again, and they were like, ‘Hey, let’s do it.’ So we did it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team’s undefeated streak to begin the season reached 13 games, and as the streak went on, the players and their unshaven legs started receiving a lot of attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“All the students every time you went to school would say, ‘Oh, I want to see your legs! I want to see how hairy they are,’” senior Leslie Handzus said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Even people from other schools,” senior Brittney Kruse added. “We went to (Southwest Star Concept) for a game and people were asking us about it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pact became so talked about that even some of the players’ mothers made a contribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The self-titled “Sasquatch Moms” created home-made hairy legs by cutting up rugs and a gorilla costume, and showed up to watch their daughters wearing the outfits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We didn’t know that was coming until they came out, and we looked, and we were like, ‘Oh my goodness,’” Brittney Kruse said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It was the most embarrassing moment of our lives,” Handzus added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the players said that the whole experience was embarrassing, but worthwhile, and was definitely a step above the alternative that was posed of going with unshaven armpits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The players felt that having hairy legs may have even helped them on the court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It was sweet,” senior Courtney Kruse said. “You honestly kind of felt faster. We thought we kind of played faster, but it was probably in our heads.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We could seriously feel the wind in our hair,” Handzus added. “It was weird.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the legs are now shaven, the Huskies won’t be slowing down any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the years, JCC has usually lacked any significantly tall players. As a result, it has relied on taking a fast-paced approach whenever it is on the court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s what we do — it’s what we’re known for,” Brittney Kruse said. “Barely ever do we get out of a press. We get out of a press at the end of the game when we’re ahead by whatever, but usually we’re pressing as much as we can, and we’re constantly going fast.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We found out that if we don’t press, we play bad,” Courtney Kruse added. “We play worse if we play slow.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The emphasis on speed has in large part been a contribution of Schuller’s. It’s a philosophy he has drilled into every one of the players since he first began coaching them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’ve been working on this pressing and running style basically since they were in eighth grade,” Schuller said. “They’ve had a lot of experience with this fast pace. I don’t think you build that in a year, it’s taken a long time to be that effective on the press and to be able to play that fast.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three seniors on the team have been playing under Schuller since they were in seventh grade, when they all were bumped up to play on the eighth grade team. Burmeister played on the same team despite being a grade younger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Schuller kept progressing from eighth grade coach to varsity coach, the three seniors and Burmeister were with him every step of the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result has been that the team has developed a very strong sense of familiarity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s an advantage we do have over people,” Schuller said. “I really know these players really well, and they know each other really well. I think that’s one of the key things for our success.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding to the familiarity is that the team is almost literally one big family, with a number of players having sisters or cousins on the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Half of us are family,” Burmeister said. “A lot of us are cousins — we’re all related somehow.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In spite of all that the team has going for it, the loss to Marshall and a further loss on Saturday against Estherville Lincoln Central has shown the team that it is not immune from losing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the team has been philosophical about the two losses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We wish we were (undefeated), but then people are like, ‘It’s probably healthy to lose once,’ because then you’re not like, ‘Oh, I’m sure we’ll win this game,’” Handzus said. “We always have to fight for every game now, because we know that’s there’s teams better than us out there.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the end of the season and the section tournament approach, Schuller knows that the team still has its toughest tests ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“As you get toward tournament time, all the teams get better,” Schuller said. “They’re better at handling the press, they’re more disciplined at getting back, so the game changes a little bit — everybody’s trying to slow it down a little bit more. We’ve got to continue to get better so we don’t allow them to, because then they force us to do things we’re not as good at.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One factor that has limited JCC’s success in the section tournament the last few years has been running into teams stacked with tall players, but Schuller doesn’t think that will pose as much of a problem this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t think the section is all tall as it has been in the past,” Schuller said. “I think that’s the difference. I don’t know if a team without a 5-11 player has ever won the section — at least for a long time since I’ve known — and we’re trying to do that.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One team that has always had enough tall players to stand in the team’s way has been Pipestone Area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Arrows have knocked the Huskies out of the section tournament in each of the past three years, and the Huskies are determined to end that streak this season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I think sometimes we don’t think we can beat them because we’ve lost to them so many times, but definitely this year’s going to be a lot different,” Handzus said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JCC was scheduled to have its first crack at PA on Monday, but the game was postponed due to Monday’s snowfall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of whether, the Huskies can create another undefeated streak — and if they do, the team has said they will again refrain from shaving their legs — the big goal for the season will be to make it all the way to the state tournament.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I think if we play aggressively and up to our potential, we definitely have a shot,” Handzus said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Burmeister feels that with the way things have turned out this season, this is the year that the Huskies are destined to fulfill their goal and make it to the state tournament.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I feel this is the year that we will go,” Burmeister said. “Next year we’ll lose three of our starters, and it’s going to be hard to come back. We’re still going to have good players, but this is the year for us. It’s bound to be us.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nordic team skis with the best at the Birkebeiner race</title>
      <link>http://danielwkerwin.com/2017/02/nordic-team-skis-with-the-best-at-the-birkebeiner-race/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danielwkerwin.com/2017/02/nordic-team-skis-with-the-best-at-the-birkebeiner-race/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Here is an article of mine that was published in The Mac Weekly on March 5, 2010 about the Macalester Nordic ski team&amp;rsquo;s results in the Birkebeiner race.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ST. PAUL - The leader of the Tour de France wears a yellow jersey, but the leader of Macalester&amp;rsquo;s Nordic ski team wears&amp;hellip; pink ski boots? At least that was the case when the team competed in the American Birkebeiner last Saturday, with Collin Cousins &amp;lsquo;10 sporting pink boots as he skied to a 32nd place finish in the race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cousins finished with an outstanding time of 2:04:57.4 in the 50 kilometer race, by far the race of his life, but he wasn&amp;rsquo;t the only Macalester skier passing scores of other racers in the field of over 8,000 competitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Everyone had good skis and good times, and Collin did extremely well, he was shooting for the top 50 but got 32nd in a pretty tough field,&amp;rdquo; coach Ari Ofsevit &amp;lsquo;06 said. &amp;ldquo;Everyone should be really happy with what they got out of the race.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cousins has skied the Birkebeiner well in the past and qualified to race in the elite wave of the field, but his result on Saturday has taken him to a whole new level in the sport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Given that I started training in January, I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to finish with the top guys, but I felt strong, pushed to my max, and had fun,&amp;rdquo; Cousins said. &amp;ldquo;The race result means that I need to make a decision whether or not to pursue racing on a professional level or continue to enjoy it casually.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ofsevit said that if Cousins chooses to focus hard on ski training after graduating in May he has the potential to have a bright future in the sport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;He&amp;rsquo;s the kind of guy that with training he could turn out some really top level results; he&amp;rsquo;s pretty darn close already,&amp;rdquo; Ofsevit said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although Cousins came into the race as a seasoned skier, most of the team was competing in the Birkebeiner for the first time. Many of these skiers were optimistic when interviewed before the race in last week&amp;rsquo;s Mac Weekly. This optimism turned out to be completely justified. Macalester placed highly compared to other collegiate teams in the event, finishing fourth in the full length Birkebeiner and first in the shorter Kortelopet race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Terence Steinberg &amp;lsquo;11 was one of the first time racers who had a good experience in not only his first ever Birkebeiner, but his first ever ski race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It was a lot easier than I thought it would be,&amp;rdquo; Steinberg said. &amp;ldquo;I was worried I&amp;rsquo;d have to go in and be humbled by the whole thing, but it was actually a huge confidence booster, which was really sweet.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emil Mellgren &amp;lsquo;10 was also racing for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Something you ask yourself is &amp;lsquo;Why am I doing this?&amp;rsquo; - your body wants you to stop, but it&amp;rsquo;s a really good feeling when you keep going,&amp;rdquo; Mellgren said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Birkebeiner has become an obsession for skiers worldwide. Mellgren experienced this when he unexpectedly ran into a family friend from Sweden while competing. The race has become so popular that fans line vast stretches of the course of the race, which ends on the streets of downtown Hayward, Wis. Tess Carley &amp;lsquo;13 appreciated the support the spectators provided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Saturday was a beautiful day and it was crazy to be amongst so many Nordic skiers,&amp;rdquo; Carley said. &amp;ldquo;All of the crazy fans cheering along the way made it easier to finish, and there was a lot of adrenaline after waking up at 5:30 to ski with 8,400 other people.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team made vast progress with all the new skiers this season, the culmination of which was seen at the Birkebeiner, boding well for the program&amp;rsquo;s future. However, the team will suffer a blow with a large proportion of the team graduating this May.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I think we fared really well as a team,&amp;rdquo; Steinberg said. &amp;ldquo;Unfortunately most of the team is seniors this year so we won&amp;rsquo;t be able to build on it as much as we could have.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However the team is always open to have new people come out and try the sport. Ofsevit stresses that the program isn&amp;rsquo;t concerned foremost with racing results, but that &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s really about going out, having a good time and improving year after year and month after month.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ofsevit will be holding a clinic this Sunday for anyone who is interested in learning how to ski, and absolute beginners are more than welcome. Details can be found alongside this article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For anyone who is interested in trying Nordic skiing, Steinberg and Mellgren are two good examples that Nordic skiing is a good way not only to get out and enjoy the winter months, but it potentially opens new doors too. Both intend to compete in a biathlon event this Sunday, the first time either will have attempted the sport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There&amp;rsquo;s just something about skiing around in the woods with a gun on your back that speaks to the Northern Swede in me,&amp;rdquo; Mellgren said. &amp;ldquo;Maybe that&amp;rsquo;ll be next year&amp;rsquo;s project.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sample Photos</title>
      <link>http://danielwkerwin.com/2017/02/sample-photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danielwkerwin.com/2017/02/sample-photos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A sample gallery of my published photos.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sample Photos</title>
      <link>http://danielwkerwin.com/2017/02/sample-photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danielwkerwin.com/2017/02/sample-photos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A sample gallery of my published photos.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A trifecta of champions</title>
      <link>http://danielwkerwin.com/2017/02/a-trifecta-of-champions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danielwkerwin.com/2017/02/a-trifecta-of-champions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Here is an article of mine that was published in the New Ulm Journal on March 4, 2012 about three Minnesota state champion high school wrestlers hailing from towns near New Ulm.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subhead: Anderson, Rose and Cooling win state wrestling titles&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ST. PAUL - In the drama of the Class A individual state wrestling tournament, dreams can either be ecstatically realized or devastatingly shattered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For River Valley senior Jacob Anderson and two other area wrestlers, the former became reality as they ended their seasons with state championships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s a dream come true, for sure,&amp;rdquo; Anderson said. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve been dreaming about this for&amp;hellip; well, the last few nights especially I&amp;rsquo;ve been dreaming about it, but ever since seventh grade I&amp;rsquo;ve been dreaming about it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anderson won the 138-pound bracket, Madelia/Truman/Martin Luther junior Adam Cooling was the champion at 145 and Sibley East sophomore Nathan Rose earned his school&amp;rsquo;s first-ever state title by winning at 195 pounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anderson entered the tournament eager to win the state title in his senior season after three previous unsuccessful attempts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He left little to chance in his championship match against Minneota&amp;rsquo;s Theodore Bueltel, racking on the points in an 18-10 decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I knew I could do it. I beat a kid ranked second in state and this kid was fifth, so I knew I could go out there and just beat him, and that&amp;rsquo;s what I did,&amp;rdquo; Anderson said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anderson earned a takedown in the first seconds of the match to take an immediate 2-0 lead and added two more takedowns to increase his lead to 6-2 at the end of the first period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anderson kept a buffer of around five points until deep in the third period, where he earned a reversal and a pair of takedowns to take a commanding lead. Bueltel showed his frustration late by resorting to pounding on Anderson&amp;rsquo;s head, leaving Anderson with a bloodied nose, but also a gold medal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anderson became the Wildcats&amp;rsquo; second state champion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;(River Valley has) two state champs now, the last one was two years ago,&amp;rdquo; Anderson said. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m glad I&amp;rsquo;m in the books.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his semifinal mach against Wabasso/Red Rock Central&amp;rsquo;s Tanner Rohlik, Anderson escaped with a 3-2 victory after a very static match.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anderson earned an early takedown to take a 2-0 advantage, then withstood a strong grip from Rohlik throughout most of the second period, taking a 3-1 lead into the third.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the third it was Anderson&amp;rsquo;s turn to take a firm grip, as he held on tightly to Rohlik right until the end of the period, when Rohlik earned an escape to make the score 3-2, but Anderson was able to close out the match in the dying seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fittingly, the match between the Wildcat and the Bobcat was wrestled on mat No. 1 - a mat featuring a jaguar logo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his first state tournament appearance last year, Rose&amp;rsquo;s path was blocked by facing the eventual champion in the first round - Frazee&amp;rsquo;s Kody Sorenson - and eventual third-place finisher Adam Josephson of Minneota in his wrestleback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year Rose met Josephson again, though this time it was in the championship match. Rose got his revenge by eking out a 5-3 decision, earning the winning points right at the end of the third period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I can&amp;rsquo;t really believe it, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d be more excited,&amp;rdquo; Rose said of winning the title. &amp;ldquo;Words can&amp;rsquo;t express it right now.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After entering the third period in the final against Josephson trailing 1-0, Rose manufactured a reversal and took a 2-1 lead. However, Josephson retook the lead with a reversal of his own to take a 3-2 lead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rose tied the score at 3-3 with an escape with 15 seconds remaining and took the lead with four seconds remaining with a reversal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I was tired, but when you know that you can do it you forget about all the tiredness and you just power through it,&amp;rdquo; Rose said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rose had nothing but respect for Josephson after the match.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;He&amp;rsquo;s a tough wrestler, he didn&amp;rsquo;t run off like most people do after losing, even if it&amp;rsquo;s their senior year,&amp;rdquo; Rose said. &amp;ldquo;I give him a lot of respect. He&amp;rsquo;s a tough wrestler.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his semifinal match earlier in the day, Rose earned a trio of first-period takedowns against Walker-Hackensack-Akeley/Nevis junior Christopher Zimmer en route to a 10-3 decision. Zimmer had been undefeated on the season prior to the match and ended up placing third.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cooling faced a familiar opponent in the 145-pound final in Atwater-Cosmos-Grave City&amp;rsquo;s Larry Bomstad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cooling lost only twice at the 2011 state tournament, but both losses came against Bomstad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I wrestled him twice last year and lost to him both times up here at state,&amp;rdquo; Cooling said. &amp;ldquo;I was kind of nervous coming in, but I knew him from wrestling last year, I knew it was going to be hard to take him down.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The match fittingly needed overtime to decide a winner, with Cooling prevailing with a 3-2 decision to earn his first state title.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not fun (going into overtime), but it&amp;rsquo;s something you&amp;rsquo;ve got to do sometimes to win a match,&amp;rdquo; Cooling said. &amp;ldquo;I knew it was going to be a tight match and I might go into overtime and I prepared myself for that mentally and just went out there and got it done.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though it was just Cooling&amp;rsquo;s first state title after a fourth-place finish last year (he lost to Bomstad in both the second round and the third-place match), it was the third state title for his family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year his brother Alex won the 160-pound state title and his cousin Andy Forstner - who is now a coach for the Jayhawks - also won a state title during his wrestling career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;That felt great,&amp;rdquo; Cooling said of continuing the family legacy. &amp;ldquo;My cousin Andy won state and he&amp;rsquo;s a coach now. It feels good to have us three all state champions together for Madelia. It just is awesome.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Cooling&amp;rsquo;s final against Bomstad, both wrestlers showed their poise by not giving up any easy points. Regulation ended with the score tied 1-1, with both wrestlers earning their points from escapes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cooling sent Bomstad to the floor in the first overtime period, but Bomstad recovered to avoid a takedown. Cooling finally broke through with a two-point reversal, after which he held on for the victory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I knew I had to pull something off, and I almost took him down a couple times, but his strength kind of helped him out,&amp;rdquo; Cooling said. &amp;ldquo;That was fine because I eventually got the win, and that&amp;rsquo;s all I was looking for.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bomstad had been undefeated on the season before his loss to Cooling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his semifinal match against Lake City&amp;rsquo;s Rusty Grisim, Cooling took an early lead, but had to hang on until the very end to earn the victory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I came in with a lot of doubts, just because I&amp;rsquo;m a nervous person,&amp;rdquo; Cooling said. &amp;ldquo;I just went out there and tried to keep my head straight and got the win.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cooling started out with a takedown to take a 2-0 lead, but his lead was down to one point at 3-2 after Grisim put him in a headlock late in the second period. However, time ran out in the period before Grisim could do too much damage to Cooling&amp;rsquo;s lead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grisim earned an escape early in the third period to tie the score, but Cooling earned a takedown with 1:23 left on the clock and earned another takedown late in the match to prevail by a 7-3 decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I needed to go out and get a takedown right away, that&amp;rsquo;s my main game plan,&amp;rdquo; Cooling said. &amp;ldquo;Once I got that takedown and rode him out I was pretty confident. Then I got thrown in a headlock, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t give up any back points, so I happy with that. Then I got the takedown in the last period.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a devastating loss in his second round match on Friday, River Valley junior Lance Briard entered Saturday&amp;rsquo;s action determined to place as well as possible in the consolation bracket at 285 pounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;After (the second-round loss) I just kind of threw it all behind me, focused on the next match and kept things rolling,&amp;rdquo; Briard said. &amp;ldquo;A loss is a loss, you&amp;rsquo;ve got to keep working.&amp;rdquo;
Briard started the day on the right foot, defeating Jackson County Central senior Alex Tewes by an 8-3 decision to guarantee himself a place in the medal rounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I knew he was a good kid and I had to keep my position,&amp;rdquo; Briard said. &amp;ldquo;I knew he was going to be looking for a headlock, so I was trying to work by slide-bys and duck-unders and things like that.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Briard wrestled hard in his consolation semifinal match, but was unable to build a lead against Lake City senior Pedro Guevara. Briard held a 1-0 lead after the second period, but Guevara earned an escape in the third to send the match into overtime tied at 1-1. Neither wrestler was able to break through until the third overtime, where Guevara ended up the victor by a 3-2 decision to send Briard to the fifth-place match.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the fifth-place match Briard had a Section 4A championship rematch with LeSueur-Henderson&amp;rsquo;s Aaron Bruihler. Briard repeated his victory from the section final, earning a 7-2 decision to take home the fifth-place medal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Briard was proud to have both River Valley wrestlers entered in the tournament end up with medals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s big for the whole school and community,&amp;rdquo; Briard said. &amp;ldquo;We don&amp;rsquo;t have the best program going on back at home, but it&amp;rsquo;s definitely working. It&amp;rsquo;s an awesome thing for the whole community.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wabasso/Red Rock senior Cody Welch breezed through the 220-pound bracket all the way to the championship match, though was left with a bitter taste in his mouth as he lost to final to Minneota senior Josh VanOverbeke by a 6-0 decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It would have been nice to get the gold medal, but silver is fine, I guess,&amp;rdquo; Welch said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making his third appearance at the state tournament, Welch finally got through the championship semifinals for the first time, earning a pin against United North Central&amp;rsquo;s Taylor Carlson in 3:15.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s a big relief,&amp;rdquo; Welch said after his semifinal match. &amp;ldquo;The last two years I&amp;rsquo;ve lost in the semifinal match and it&amp;rsquo;s nice to finally get past it this year.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welch&amp;rsquo;s deep tournament run was the fulfillment of a goal that his family had held for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s going to mean a lot,&amp;rdquo; Welch said. &amp;ldquo;My dad&amp;rsquo;s always wanted one of his kids to make it, and I&amp;rsquo;m the second boy in the family, and my brother didn&amp;rsquo;t make it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VanOverbeke also provided Welch&amp;rsquo;s only loss in the Section 3A tournament, which came in the section final.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wabasso/Red Rock Central had four wrestlers entered in championship semifinals at the beginning of the day, but Welch was the only one of the four to earn a spot in a championship match.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;W/RRC senior Mitchell Rohlik cruised in qualifying for his semifinal match at 152 pounds, but was unable to get much going against semifinal opponent Curt Maas (41-1 record entering the match), a senior from Medford. Rohlik fell by an 8-2 decision in the match.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mitchell Rohlik then rebounded in his consolation semifinal match, edging Aitkin senior Jordan Chouanard by a 3-2 decision to enter the third-place match against Jackson County Central&amp;rsquo;s Luke Norland. Rohlik won the match by an 8-0 major decision to claim the third-place medal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bobcats senior Brandon Goblirsch was agonizingly close to qualifying for the final at 120, but fell victim to a late takedown in his match against Wabasha-Kellogg&amp;rsquo;s Mick Roemer and was defeated by a 7-6 decision. Goblirsch was ahead 6-5 after an escape late in the third period, but Roemer manufactured the match-deciding takedown with 22 seconds remaining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goblirsch lost his consolation semifinal against Kimball Area&amp;rsquo;s Tanner Mills via fall in 1:23, but ended up taking the fifth-place medal by defeating St. James junior Richy Soto 8-1 in the fifth-place match.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After losing to Anderson in the championship semifinals, Tanner Rohlik fell by an 8-0 decision against Holdingford senior Michael Jarnot in the consolation semifinals. Rohlik took fifth place by defeating Eden Valley-Watkins&amp;rsquo; Cain Renner by a 10-5 decision in the fifth-place match.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sibley East&amp;rsquo;s Aaron Bates began the day in the championship semifinals at 160, but fell all the way to sixth place by the end of the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bates was defeated by Kerkhoven-Murdock-Sunburg&amp;rsquo;s Jordan Rothers in his championship semifinal match by a 12-1 major decision. Bates wrestled a neck-and-neck match with Kimball Area&amp;rsquo;s Jordan Joseph in the consolation semifinals, but lost in a 3-2 decision to leave him in the fifth-place match, where he was pinned by Lake City&amp;rsquo;s Will Balow in 3:22.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After entering the tournament with six wrestlers, St. James ended up with just a single wrestler entering the medal rounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Juniors Cody Hanson (106 pounds) and Richy Soto (120) were the only Saints to advance to Saturday action, with both beginning that day in the consolation quarterfinals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hanson was defeated in a 7-2 decision by Chatfield&amp;rsquo;s Hank Friederichs to end his tournament, but Soto won his consolation quarterfinal match over Pierz&amp;rsquo;s Chris Ortman to guarantee himself a finish of no worse than sixth place in his first state tournament appearance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soto ran into tough competition the rest of the way and ended up placing sixth. He fell to New Richland-Hartland-Ellendale-Geneva senior by an 8-3 decision in the consolation semifinals to leave him in the fifth-place match, where he lost to Goblirsch by an 8-1 decision.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twins Caravan hits New Ulm</title>
      <link>http://danielwkerwin.com/2017/02/twins-caravan-hits-new-ulm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danielwkerwin.com/2017/02/twins-caravan-hits-new-ulm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Here is an article of mine that was published in the New Ulm Journal on January 16, 2013 in which I interviewed members of the Minnesota Twins during their Winter Caravan stop in New Ulm.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NEW ULM - Minnesota Twins second-year infielder Brian Dozier is quickly learning how to show his appreciation to the fans, taking part in the Twins&amp;rsquo; Winter Caravan leg that stopped at KNUJ in New Ulm on Tuesday morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He&amp;rsquo;s having a harder time learning how to dress appropriately in the Minnesota winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A native of Mississippi, Dozier received plenty of flack from his fellow three tour members - manager Ron Gardenhire, bench coach Terry Steinbach and TV broadcaster Dick Bremer - for the winter coat he brought on the tour, which Gardenhire said &amp;ldquo;should be on a space shuttle and not in Minnesota.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;ve been giving Dozier a bad time, because he flies up from Mississippi, and we&amp;rsquo;re like nine below, and he&amp;rsquo;s got some little light jacket that he&amp;rsquo;s running around town, and he&amp;rsquo;s here for two weeks,&amp;rdquo; Steinbach said. &amp;ldquo;We were teasing him about going over to Scheel&amp;rsquo;s when we were in Mankato, &amp;lsquo;You&amp;rsquo;d better go buy yourself a better coat.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Receiving good-natured ribbing from veterans of the franchise is all part of the experience for younger players taking part in the Winter Caravan, a two-week long tour of Minnesota and neighboring states that gives members of the Twins organization a chance to greet fans and get them excited about the upcoming season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Fans spend all year round coming to watch us play and watching us on TV and stuff, it&amp;rsquo;s just a good thing to give back and to see those fans, to interact with them,&amp;rdquo; Dozier said. &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s what it&amp;rsquo;s all about, it&amp;rsquo;s all about the fans and just to interact with those people, and to shake hands and tell stories with fans around Minnesota and other states that are Twins fans.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Winter Caravan, which is being held this year for the 53rd time, consists of many different legs comprised of different personnel. The leg that reached New Ulm on Tuesday morning kicked off on Monday with an event in Minneapolis, then made stops in Northfield and Mankato before arriving in New Ulm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The caravan only had time for a brief stop in New Ulm, arriving at the private event at KNUJ at 8:15 a.m. and leaving shortly before 9:30 a.m. to head to a stop at Sleepy Eye Elementary School.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steinbach, a New Ulm native, was making an appearance in New Ulm for one of the first times since being named as the Twins&amp;rsquo; new bench coach in the offseason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s exciting for me,&amp;rdquo; Steinbach said of his new role. &amp;ldquo;To spend a large part of my life in baseball, then to get out for a little bit and have the opportunity to get back in at the major league level is really exciting for me. I&amp;rsquo;m really looking forward to the opportunity.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gardenhire, who was part of former Twins manger Tom Kelly&amp;rsquo;s staff when Steinbach played catcher for the Twins in the late 1990s, was excited that his good friend Steinbach was eager to come on board when the team offered him the bench coach position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This was an easy hire for me,&amp;rdquo; Gardenhire said. &amp;ldquo;Once Terry Ryan wanted to make some moves, I said, &amp;lsquo;Well, Terry Steinbach would be my first choice as a bench coach.&amp;rsquo; He has knowledge of the game, the whole package, I know him very well and I&amp;rsquo;m very comfortable around him. He&amp;rsquo;s going to help Joe Mauer, believe it or not - I know Joe&amp;rsquo;s an All Star, but the mental part of the game, I think Steiny&amp;rsquo;s really going to help him out an awful lot in calling games, and be able to pick his brain. I think they&amp;rsquo;re both going to be better for it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After enduring consecutive losing seasons, Gardenhire - entering his 12th year as Twins manager - is intent on spreading a positive message about the team&amp;rsquo;s future during the tour rather than focusing on negativity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;ve had enough negative talk, bad seasons, bad this and that - that&amp;rsquo;s in the past, just like the good seasons are in the past,&amp;rdquo; Gardenhire said. &amp;ldquo;Now we&amp;rsquo;ve just got to worry about getting back to having some fun and playing the game and respecting the game. I&amp;rsquo;m trying to send out positive vibes. I know there&amp;rsquo;s been a lot of talk about, &amp;lsquo;Well the Twins may not do that well this year.&amp;rsquo; My statement to that is, &amp;lsquo;How do you know?&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dozier, who Gardenhire describes as a &amp;ldquo;nice looking player&amp;rdquo; following an up-and-down season last year, is also focusing on looking forward to the team&amp;rsquo;s potential in the upcoming season rather than at its shortfalls from last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I know talking to all the guys this offseason, we still have a lot to prove from the year that we had last year, and no one&amp;rsquo;s more disappointed than we are, I can promise you that,&amp;rdquo; Dozier said. &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re ready to get back out, and we&amp;rsquo;re all excited, so we&amp;rsquo;ll hit the ground running come spring.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tours like the Twins&amp;rsquo; Winter Caravan are rare in professional sports, with most Major League Baseball teams waiting until Spring Training to come together for the first time. Bremer is one that appreciates the unique way that the Winter Caravan puts Twins personnel in touch with fans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s a nice reminder for all of us - the manager, the coaches, the players, and the broadcasters, too - about how much impact we have in their lives during the season,&amp;rdquo; said Bremer, who is entering his 30th season with the team. &amp;ldquo;When over the course of the season you&amp;rsquo;re so wrapped up in what you&amp;rsquo;re doing, sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s easy to forget how much of an impact this team has in the region. In the winter time one of the really neat things is being reminded of that.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After continuing on to Sleepy Eye, the tour leg stopped in Worthington before wrapping up its Tuesday schedule in Sioux Falls, S.D. It will continue today with a stop in Yankton, S.D., and a pair of stops in Iowa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Our job on this caravan and what we want to do is say thanks to all our fans,&amp;rdquo; Gardenhire said. &amp;ldquo;I know it hasn&amp;rsquo;t been easy, but the greatest thing about Minnesota Twins fans is most of them forget really quick, and they just can&amp;rsquo;t wait for the season&amp;hellip; that&amp;rsquo;s the part that we like, that&amp;rsquo;s the people that we want to talk to and say thank you, and we&amp;rsquo;re going to give you our best.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At arm’s strength: Rushmore’s Richard Lupkes wins world armwrestling title</title>
      <link>http://danielwkerwin.com/2017/02/at-arms-strength-rushmores-richard-lupkes-wins-world-armwrestlingtitle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danielwkerwin.com/2017/02/at-arms-strength-rushmores-richard-lupkes-wins-world-armwrestlingtitle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Here is an article of mine that was published in the Worthington Daily Globe on December 27, 2010 about a world champion armwrestler Richard Lupkes.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RUSHMORE — Richard Lupkes faced a dilemma.
 
At 54 years old, the farmer from Rushmore was in a position to try to add a second world title to his long list of armwrestling accomplishments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stage was set — this year’s World Armwrestling Federation (WAF) world championships were to be held in the U.S., in Mesquite, Nev., and Lupkes was coming off of titles that he won in both the superheavyweight open division and superheavyweight grand master division at the national championships in Billings, Mont., in August.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then Lupkes was given an opportunity that he couldn’t turn down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was one of eight elite armwrestlers invited to the invitation-only “Arm Wars ‘Sin City’” supermatch in Las Vegas, an event put on by world-renowned British armwrestling promoter Neil Pickup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem was that Lupkes wouldn’t be able to compete for the world title in the open division in Mesquite on Dec. 11 and also participate in “Arm Wars,” the following day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lupkes decided to pull out of the open division at the world championships — the main event, in which he had won his world title in Eskilstuna, Sweden in 1988 — and decided to enter only in the grand master division, the category reserved for competitors 50 and over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I didn’t want to take a chance of tiring my arm out,” Lupkes said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite passing up the chance of a title in the open division, Lupkes seized his opportunity in the grand master division.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I actually felt pretty confident,” Lupkes said. “I trained really hard, so if I wouldn’t have won I would have been really disappointed. I felt good.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lupkes beat competitors from Azerbaijan, Russia, Canada and France to reach the final in the double-elimination competition, where he was paired up once more with Minabaddin Gurbanov — the competitor from Azerbaijan whom he had defeated earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His second match against Gurbanov ended with the same result as the first, giving Lupkes the superheavyweight grand master world title.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lupkes had some regrets leaving the world championships early to compete in “Arm Wars.” The event in Mesquite was the biggest armwrestling competition ever to be held in the US, with 1,313 competitors from 43 countries in attendance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But he knew by then it was too late to change his mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“After being at the worlds and seeing the venue and all the competitors, I kind of had some second thoughts,” Lupkes said. “I kind of wish I wouldn’t have pulled the open, but it’s too late then already.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, “Arm Wars” provided a great opportunity for Lupkes to compete in a very different environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It was exciting — just to be invited was something,” Lupkes said. “To be there with that class of armwrestlers — I mean, they were all world-class armwrestlers, there was nobody there that’s bad — it’s pretty amazing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lupkes was matched up against the best of the world-class armwrestlers in the first round, Britain’s Devon Larratt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I had to pull the No. 1 ranked guy in the world my first round, Devon Larratt,” Lupkes said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You armwrestle six times in a row with only a minute break between rounds. It was totally different for me, and I was old enough to be everybody’s dad there, basically.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lupkes was close to winning the first round against Larratt, but Larratt slipped through his grasp. Larratt then won the next five in a row, handing Lupkes a first round loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Lupkes then swept his ensuing matches against Ryan Espay — the Canadian national champion — and Tim Bresnan, a former world champion from Connecticut, to finish on a high note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although disappointed, Lupkes said that “It turned out OK.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Few people would be upset losing to the top-ranked armwrestler in the world, but Lupkes isn’t used to losing. Asked what percentage of his matches he estimates he has won during his career, Lupkes responded, “Since I started armwrestling, probably 99 percent. I’ve been pretty fortunate so far, except against Devon.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lupkes learned later that he currently is the No. 1 ranked armwrestler in the U.S., and the No. 2 ranked armwrestler in the world — making his expectations to win every match understandable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ve always probably been in the top-10 I suppose, but to be honest with you I don’t really pay that much attention to (the rankings),” Lupkes said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite his accomplishments, Lupkes doesn’t consider himself to be particularly famous — despite the fact that in Mesquite he was asked by numerous people to have his photograph taken with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“People would come up and say, ‘Can I have my picture taken with you?’ and they wouldn’t speak English, but they would want pictures,” said Shirley Lupkes, Richard’s wife. “The respect that they have for Rich is just awesome.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Richard Lupkes doesn’t consider the attention he received as particularly proving his fame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s maybe just because I’ve been in the sport a long time,” Lupkes said. “I don’t really consider myself famous or anything. I’ve just been in the sport a long time, so I’ve been around a lot, and I think that’s really the only reason.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is that in the USA, armwrestling has never gained widespread popularity. The 1987 Sylvester Stallone movie “Over the Top” and the accompanying tournament in Las Vegas — which until this year’s world championships was the biggest ever armwrestling tournament in the U.S. — brought some attention to the sport, but since then, Lupkes says media attention towards the sport has waned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Once in a while you’ll see it on ESPN, but it seems like it’s actually gotten a little quieter if anything,” he said. “The sport is actually really growing in the country, there’s a lot more competitors. It seems like now with the Internet and stuff people are a little more interested in keeping track of who’s pulling where. It’s easier to communicate I guess.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sport is far more popular in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pickup has invited Lupkes to compete in another “Arm Wars” event, this time in England. The event will be aired on Eurosport — a European sports network comparable to ESPN in the U.S. — where the estimated audience for the sport is around 200 million viewers from between 50-60 countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s way bigger in Europe,” Richard Lupkes said. “They watch armwrestling like we watch football over here — that would be a comparison. It’s a lot more popular over there.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Lupkes will have to weigh the offer before committing to the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although Lupkes is advancing in years, and has undergone surgery for a number of injuries recently, he will continue armwrestling competitively as long as he can, even in the open division.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s definitely not getting any easier,” Lupkes said. “It seems that these young kids are getting bigger and stronger all the time. If I would just stay in my own age group I think I could do well for a long time, but I always end up getting in the open class because that’s really where it’s at.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lupkes is unsure whether he will be able to compete in next year’s WAF world championships in Kazakhstan, or the 2012 world championships in Rio De Janeiro, Brazil — both locations that pose logistical difficulties for Lupkes to defend his grand master world title and attempt another open division world title.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that’s certain is that Lupkes will continue weight training — his primary passion, from which he says his armwrestling career developed as a “byproduct from spending time in the gym” — and embracing his new role as a personal trainer at Anytime Fitness in Worthington.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Lupkes does find himself at a tournament in the future, he is bound to be received as one of the most respected armwrestlers, whether he considers himself to be famous or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Going to the tournaments is a lot of fun, because, I always say, it’s like a family reunion,” Lupkes said. “You get to see your old friends and people you don’t see but maybe once or twice a year. You get to meet a lot of new people, see the new armwrestlers coming into the sport, and that’s always a lot of fun, too.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>