<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio on Daniel Kerwin</title>
    <link>http://danielwkerwin.com/categories/portfolio/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Portfolio on Daniel Kerwin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://danielwkerwin.com/categories/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Samples</title>
      <link>http://danielwkerwin.com/2017/02/writing-samples/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danielwkerwin.com/2017/02/writing-samples/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;I have chosen a variety of my published articles from throughout my career to provide samples of my writing. You will find these articles below, grouped together by publication.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;2015 Pacific Games&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Here are some articles I wrote during my time working for the Games News Service at 2015 Pacific Games in Port Moresby, Papua New Guinea.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a July 8, 2015 article about Papua New Guinean weightlifter Steven Kari: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fijitimes.com/story.aspx?id=313022&#34;&gt;Kari delivers two gold for home crowd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a July 13, 2015 article about the open water swimming competition: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.emtv.com.pg/sport/2015/07/new-caledonia-swimmers-cap-supremacy-with-open-water-double/&#34;&gt;New Caledonia Swimmers Cap Supremacy with Open Water Double&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;New Ulm Journal&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Here are some articles I wrote during my time working for the New Ulm Journal in New Ulm, Minnesota from 2011-2013.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an article of mine that was published in the New Ulm Journal on March 4, 2012 about three Minnesota state champion high school wrestlers hailing from towns near New Ulm: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.danielwkerwin.com/2017/02/a-trifecta-of-champions/&#34;&gt;A trifecta of champions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an article of mine that was published in the New Ulm Journal on January 16, 2013 in which I interviewed members of the Minnesota Twins during their winter caravan stop in New Ulm: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.danielwkerwin.com/2017/02/twins-caravan-hits-new-ulm/&#34;&gt;Twins Caravan hits New Ulm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Worthington Daily Globe&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Here are some articles I wrote during my time working for the Worthington Daily Globe in Worthington, Minnesota from 2010-2011.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an article of mine that was published in the Worthington Daily Globe on December 27, 2010 about a world champion armwrestler Richard Lupkes.: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.danielwkerwin.com/2017/02/at-arms-strength-rushmores-richard-lupkes-wins-world-armwrestlingtitle/&#34;&gt;At arm’s strength: Rushmore’s Richard Lupkes wins world armwrestling title&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an article of mine that was published in the Worthington Daily Globe on February 1, 2011 about the Jackson County Central girls’ basketball team’s pursuit of qualifying for the state tournament.: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.danielwkerwin.com/2017/02/huskies-on-the-prowl-jackson-county-central-groomed-for-state-tourney-run/&#34;&gt;Huskies on the prowl: Jackson County Central groomed for state tourney run&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Mac Weekly&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Here are some articles I wrote during my time working for Macalester College student newspaper from 2006-2010.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an article of mine that was published in The Mac Weekly on April 10, 2009, in which I interviewed renowned historian Howard Zinn: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.danielwkerwin.com/2017/02/zinn-takes-on-just-wars-at-inaugural-philosophy-colloquium/&#34;&gt;Zinn takes on &amp;lsquo;just&amp;rsquo; wars at inaugural philosophy colloquium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an article of mine that was published in The Mac Weekly on February 26, 2010 about the Macalester Nordic ski team’s participation in the Birkebeiner race: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.danielwkerwin.com/2017/02/birkebeiner-is-baptism-by-fire-for-rookie-nordic-skiers/&#34;&gt;Birkebeiner is baptism by fire for rookie Nordic skiers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sample Photos</title>
      <link>http://danielwkerwin.com/2017/02/sample-photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danielwkerwin.com/2017/02/sample-photos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A sample gallery of my published photos.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>